

# Elena Gutiérrez

 Age: 26 (10 nov., 1993)
 Address: Madrid (28030), España

 Tel.: +34 696 073 505
 Email: elenagutiv@gmail.com

Web: <u>elenagutiv.github.io</u> LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/elena-gutierrez-viedma/</u>

## Objective

Contribute to the solution and communication of the next generation of research challenges in the fields of program analysis and verification, ML and NLP applications, using my mathematical background and research experience on the theory of formal languages for software verification.

## **Computer Skills**

- o C, Python, Octave, Bash, Prolog, HTML, CSS | General experience
- o C++, Java | Basic experience
- Git, LaTex, Keynote
- Mac OS, Linux

## Work Experience

IMDEA Software Institute

Madrid, Spain
Researcher (predoctoral researcher until Sep. 2020)

Sep. 2016 - present

National Institute of Informatics (Erato MMSD Project)

6-months research internship

Tokyo, Japan

May. 2019 - Nov. 2019

IMDEA Software InstituteMadrid, Spain3-month research internshipssummers 2013, 2014 and 2015

#### Education

Ph.D. in Software, Systems and Computing

With cum laude distinction

Double Degree in Mathematics and Software Engineering

Average grade: 8.2/10

Univ. Politécnica de Madrid
Sep. 2016 - Sep. 2020

Univ. Autónoma de Madrid
Sep. 2011 - May. 2016

#### **Courses and Certificates**

Course on Machine Learning by Andrew Ng - Coursera
 School on Formal Verification - The Hebrew University (Jerusalem)
 TOEFL iBT | Test score: 104/120
 Mar. 2020 - present
 17 - 21 Dec. 2017
 Feb. 2016

## **Software Projects**

- o Genetic algorithm (in C) for the analysis of recurrent neural networks (2020). GitHub
- o Optimization algorithm (in Prolog) for Horn clause programs (2016). GitHub

Ph.D. Thesis New Perspectives on Classical Automata Constructions Sep. 2020

Natural Languages Spanish | Native English | Advanced French | Basic

#### **Volunteer Work and Interests**

- Soñar Despierto Foundation: Giving support lessons to high-school students coming from marginalised backgrounds in Madrid (Sep. 2018 - May. 2019)
- AFS Intercultura Spain: Participating in the coordination of intercultural activities with foreign students from exchange programs (Sep. 2011 - May. 2012)
- I love sports, especially running (medium: 10 km, and large distance: 21 km), cycling and paddle tennis.